A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Welfare Interests - General Files, Series P FA325
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Cleveland Projects
  - Cleveland Projects - Cleveland Orchestra Concerts, 1886-1949 (Box 26, Folder 271)
    John D. Rockefeller's first contribution was of $5,000 to the Cleveland Music Hall. This was followed by gifts for special purposes and for underwriting deficits. John D. Rockefeller was a Guarantor for the Orchestra. Starr J. Murphy stopped the underwriting in 1916. There was a personal friendship between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Mrs. Hughes. An endowment gift was made in 1929. Tickets were purchased throughout the period. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Adella P. Hughes.
  - Cleveland Projects - Cleveland Public Library, 1908-1932 (Box 26, Folder 272)
    John D. Rockefeller gave $3,600 toward purchase of a lot for the library in 1916. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined all requests, including one to give for a library memorial to his violin teacher, Mr. Beck. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Cleveland Projects - Cleveland School of Art, 1899-1941 (Box 26, Folder 273)
    $700 annual contribution given from 1905 to 1915. Requests for the endowment were declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Cleveland Projects - Miscellaneous Appeals, 1921-1939 (Box 26, Folder 274)
    Small contributions to various Cleveland civic projects but individual and hospital appeals were declined. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
  - Cleveland Projects - Miscellaneous Appeals, 1944-1961 (Box 26, Folder 275)
  - Cleveland Projects - Miscellaneous Appeals, 1957-1961 (Box 26, Folder 0275A)
  - Cleveland Projects - Miscellaneous Appeals - Cleveland Association for Criminal Justice, 1922 (Box 26, Folder 276)
  - Cleveland Projects - Cleveland Foundation, 1913-1956 (Box 26, Folder 277)
    A fund to accept bequests for philanthropic purposes in Cleveland. There was consideration of a possible gift by John D. Rockefeller but no action was taken. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.
  - Cleveland Projects - Phillis Wheatley Association, 1924-1932 (Box 26, Folder 278)
    Home for colored girls in Cleveland appealed to the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial Fund for aid. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $100,000 toward the building fund, and small gifts for special purposes. The Association was connected with the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) of Cleveland. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Woods, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Cleveland Projects - Phillis Wheatley Association, 1924, 1933-1955 (Box 26, Folder 279)
  - Cleveland Projects - Case Institute of Technology, 1902-1926 (Box 27, Folder 280)
    Starr J. Murphy report on school. John D. Rockefeller gave $200,000 in 1904 but declined appeals in 1912 and 1926. Laurance S. Rockefeller gave a gift in 1953. All other appeals were declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy.
    Folder reviewed and opened by KWR and TR, December 29, 2003.
    See also Box 57, Folder 639.
  - Cleveland Projects - Case Institute of Technology, 1953-1961 (Box 27, Folder 281)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller gave a gift in 1953. All other appeals were declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy.
  - Cleveland Projects - Case Institute of Technology, 1953-1961 (Box 27, Folder 0281A)
  - Cleveland Projects - Legal Size Material (Box 55, Folder 619)
    Folders 255-280.
  - Cleveland Projects - Case Institute of Technology (Box 57, Folder 639)
    House lots on Case Avenue, Case School of Applied Sciences. Drawn by W. J. Morgan and Co. Lithographers.
    Removed from Box 27, Folder 280.
- Homes
  - Homes - General, 1922-1950 (Box 27, Folder 282)
    Contributions to homes for working girls, children, and the aged. Small intermittent contributions were given, but most appeals were declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard.
    47
  - Homes - General, 1922-1950 (Box 27, Folder 0282A)
  - Homes - General, 1950-1954 (Box 27, Folder 283)
  - Homes - General, 1950-1954 (Box 27, Folder 0283A)
  - Homes - General, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 284)
  - Homes - General, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 0284A)
  - Homes - General, 1956-1961 (Box 27, Folder 285)
  - Homes - General, 1958-1961 (Box 27, Folder 0285A)
  - Homes - Friendly League for Christian Service, Inc., 1922-1952 (Box 27, Folder 286)
    The League grew out of the Billy Sunday Crusade. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $1,000 in 1944.
  - Homes - Jennie Clarkson Home for Children, 1923-1958 (Box 27, Folder 287)
  - Homes - Jennie Clarkson Home for Children, 1923-1958 (Box 27, Folder 0287A)
  - Homes - American Female Guardian Society, 1897-1919 (Box 27, Folder 288)
    An annual gift of $500 was given to the Society which worked with children and operated an industrial school. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller.
    47.1
  - Homes - Gould Farm, 1916-1934 (Box 27, Folder 289)
    This was a home for people with various emotional problems, a place to recuperate and regain spiritual strength. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. became interested when an employee of his was sent there. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $5,000, followed by other large gifts for specific needs of the Farm. His final gift was given in 1943. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Mrs. William Gould.
  - Homes - Gould Farm, 1934-1956 (Box 28, Folder 290)
  - Homes - Edgewater Creche, 1900-1935 (Box 28, Folder 291)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made several small gifts in the 1920s, some later. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., B. Houston.
    47.2
  - Homes - Father Flanagan's Boys Town, 1936-1961 (Box 28, Folder 292)
    A steady flow of appeals to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and sons was ignored on the grounds of a policy against giving to individual homes except in cities of family residence.
    47.3
  - Homes - Congregational Home for the Aged, Brooklyn, 1914-1941 (Box 28, Folder 293)
    Lucy Spelman was interested and gave small annual gifts. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. was not interested. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    47.4
  - Homes - Craig Colony for Epileptics, 1922-1933 (Box 28, Folder 294)
    This was an appeal for construction of a Protestant chapel at the State institution. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledged $1,500 but the pledge lapsed. Later, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made small contributions totaling $3,500. The chapel was completed in 1933. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
    47.41
  - Homes - Robins' Nest, Tarrytown, 1909-1932 (Box 28, Folder 295)
    Small annual contributions by John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    47.5
  - Homes - Greer School, 1917-1961 (Box 28, Folder 296)
    47.6
  - Homes - Greer School, 1917-1961 (Box 28, Folder 0296A)
  - Homes - Greer School - Contributions, 1907-1959 (Box 28, Folder 297)
    Gifts by Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller.
    See also Box 56, Folders 632-633.
  - Homes - Greer School - Contributions, 1907-1959 (Box 28, Folder 0297A)
  - Homes - Florence Crittenton League, 1933-1957 (Box 28, Folder 298)
    This was a shelter for runaways or girls in various kinds of trouble. Abby Aldrich Rockefeller contributed, 1944-1947. Other members of the family declined requests.
    47.7
  - Homes - Florence Crittenton League, 1933-1957 (Box 28, Folder 0298A)
  - Homes - Leake and Watts Orphan House, 1919-1957 (Box 28, Folder 299)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave in 1919 and 1920 to this Protestant orphanage. Then his advisors questioned the efficacy of institutional care as opposed to foster homes of adoption. The orphanage switched its role to a "model school (boarding) for dependent children." John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed from 1925-1928 but later requests were denied on policy grounds. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Thomas B. Appleget.
    47.8
  - Homes - Peabody Home for Aged and Indigent Females, 1934-1961 (Box 28, Folder 300)
    A private, free home for "needy gentlewomen," its form requests were denied until 1957 when Mary French Rockefeller began small annual contributions. Correspondents include Mary French Rockefeller.
    47.9
  - Homes - Sheltering Arms Children's Service, 1945-1960 (Box 29, Folder 301)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller gave $5,000 in 1946. The Rockefeller Brothers Fund gave $20,000 toward the building fund in 1959. All other appeals were ignored. Correspondents include Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Arthur Jones, Dana S. Creel.
    47.10
  - Homes - Irvington House, 1935-1960 (Box 29, Folder 302)
    Winthrop Rockefeller gave a small contribution to this home for children with heart disease. correspondents include Winthrop Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, Arthur W. Packard.
    47.11
  - Homes - Irvington House, 1958-1960 (Box 29, Folder 0302A)
  - Homes - St. Faith's House, Tarrytown, 1910-1927 (Box 29, Folder 303)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave annually to this house for unwed mothers but stopped when the House's finances got more tangled. The House closed, then reopened with the aid of a legacy, and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. resumed contributions. In 1948 Mary French Rockefeller became the Vice-President of the House, and she headed the 1950 Building Fund Campaign. Family members gave some special gifts to the campaign, but later appeals were declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mary French Rockefeller.
    47.13
  - Homes - St. Faith's House, Tarrytown, 1928-1954 (Box 29, Folder 304)
    See also Box 57, Folder 640.
  - Homes - St. Faith's House, Tarrytown - Contributions, 1929-1930 (Box 29, Folder 305)
  - Homes - St. Faith's House, Tarrytown - Contributions, 1931-1939 (Box 29, Folder 306)
  - Homes - St. Faith's House, Tarrytown - Contributions, 1947-1961 (Box 29, Folder 307)
  - Homes - St. Faith's House, Tarrytown - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Pledge, 1931 (Box 29, Folder 308)
  - Homes - St. Faith's House, Tarrytown - Campaign Pamphlet, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 309)
  - Homes - Inwood House, New York City, 1912-1957 (Box 29, Folder 310)
    This home was for the rehabilitation of unwed mothers. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. requested information from the Home when he was organizing the Bureau of Social Hygiene. He gave annual donations from 1912-1923 but made no contributions after 1923. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Arthur w. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    47.15
  - Homes - The Emergency Shelter, Inc., 1935-1961 (Box 29, Folder 311)
    This was a shelter for the unemployed, destitute, and homeless. All appeals were ignored. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    47.16
  - Homes - The Emergency Shelter, Inc., 1958 (Box 29, Folder 0311A)
  - Homes and Jewish Organizations - Legal Size Material (Box 55, Folder 620)
    Folders 285-344.
  - Homes - Greer School - Contributions, 2 items (Box 56, Folder 632)
    Statement of Receipts and Disbursements and Balance Sheet, both for years ending December 31, 1947, 1946, and 1945 and comparison.
    Removed from Box 28, Folder 297.
  - Homes - Greer School - Contributions (Box 56, Folder 633)
    Balance Sheet, December 31, 1947 and 1948, and comparison.
  - Homes - St. Faith's House, Tarrytown (Box 57, Folder 640)
    Comparison of finances for the years 1929-1935.
    Removed from Box 29, Folder 304.
- Immigration
  - Immigration, 1923-1958 (Box 29, Folder 312)
    Requests for family support of various organizations were declined. There is some printed material on the immigration question here. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Robert W. Gumbel, Arthur Young, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    63
    See also Box 56, Folder 636.
  - Immigration - North American Civic League for Immigrants, 1910-1919 (Box 30, Folder 313)
    John D. Rockefeller contributed annually from 1911-1915. Later requests were denied. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller.
  - Immigration - Society for Italian Immigrants, 1909-1918 (Box 30, Folder 314)
    John D. Rockefeller gave to the Society's budget for immigrant aid work from 1909-1917. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, John D. Rockefeller.
    63.1
  - Immigration - International Social Service, 1924-1934 (Box 30, Folder 315)
    This organization was known as the International Migration Service until 1947. This was organized in assist immigrants in new homes. Contributions were made by the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial Fund, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, and the Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Mary Clark Rockefeller, Mary C. Rockefeller Strawbridge, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Immigration - International Social Service, 1938-1962 (Box 30, Folder 316)
    This organization was known as the International Migration Service until 1947. This was organized in assist immigrants in new homes. Contributions were made by the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial Fund, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, and the Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Mary Clark Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Immigration - International Social Service, 1938-1962 (Box 30, Folder 316A)
  - Immigration - International Institute of New York City, Inc., 1946-1950 (Box 30, Folder 317)
    This was originally part of the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA). John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave a gift in 1946. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    63.2
  - Immigration - International Institute of New York City, Inc., 1946-1950 (Box 30, Folder 0317A)
  - Immigration - Foreign Language Information Service, 1921-1933 (Box 30, Folder 318)
    The Service provided information on American for foreign language newspapers. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $25,000 each in 1921 and 1922, $5,000 each in 1929 and 1930, and $2,500 in 1931. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Thomas B. Appleget, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    63.3
  - Immigration - Neighborhood Teacher Association, 1924-1934 (Box 30, Folder 319)
    Efforts to bring English-language teaching and other education to women in foreign-born districts. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed from 1926-1931. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard.
    63.31
  - Immigration - National League for American Citizenship, Inc., 1925-1942 (Box 30, Folder 320)
    The League provided education for immigrants. Small contributions were made from 1926-1931. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard.
    63.32
  - Immigration (Box 56, Folder 636)
    Roberts, Kenneth L., "Slow Poison," "The Saturday Evening Post," February 2, 1924.
    Removed from Box 29, Folder 312.
- Jewish Organizations
  - Jewish Organizations - Jewish Questions and Philanthropic Societies, 1926-1960 (Box 30, Folder 321)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed to various causes, but most appeals were declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Stephen Wise.
    50.1
  - Jewish Organizations - Jewish Questions and Philanthropic Societies, 1926-1960 (Box 30, Folder 0321A)
  - Jewish Organizations - Jewish Questions and Philanthropic Societies - Russian Agricultural Fund, 1928 (Box 30, Folder 322)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $500,000 toward Jewish agricultural and colonization work in Russia.
  - Jewish Organizations - Jewish Questions and Philanthropic Societies - Young Men's Hebrew Association, 1927-1933 (Box 30, Folder 323)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $50,000 toward the building fund.
  - Jewish Organizations - Jewish Questions and Philanthropic Societies - Hebrew Technical School for Girls, 1905-1906 (Box 30, Folder 324)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $5,000 toward the building fund.
  - Jewish Organizations - Jewish Questions and Philanthropic Societies - Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association, 1948-1955 (Box 30, Folder 325)
    All appeals were declined.
  - Jewish Organizations - Jewish Questions and Philanthropic Societies - B'nai B'rith, 1950-1961 (Box 30, Folder 326)
  - Jewish Organizations - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York, 1931-1961 (Box 31, Folder 327)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. strongly approved of the federative principle. He helped the Federation in its early years with $50,000 annually from 1926-1931. His gifts were gradually cut due to policy reasons. The Davison Fund gave gifts. In 1950, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $100,000 to the Capital Funds campaign and thereby became a "founder." There is information about Joseph Wilden's 1961 address advocating less sectarianism in Jewish agencies. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd., Arthur Jones, Paul Warburg.
    50.2
  - Jewish Organizations - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 0327A)
  - Jewish Organizations - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York - Contributions, 1926-1943 (Box 31, Folder 328)
  - Jewish Organizations - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York - Contributions, 1944-1959 (Box 31, Folder 329)
  - Jewish Organizations - Jewish Exiles and Refugees, 1936-1961 (Box 31, Folder 330)
    There are details about the Rockefeller Foundation's aid to emigrating scholars. The family declined appeals. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
    50.3
  - Jewish Organizations - Jewish Exiles and Refugees - American Committee for Christian German Refugees, 1937-1943 (Box 31, Folder 331)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. donated a porcelain vase to be auctioned to raise funds.
  - Jewish Organizations - Jewish Exiles and Refugees - National Committee Against Nazi Persecution and Extermination of the Jews, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 332)
  - Jewish Organizations - United Jewish Appeal of Greater New York, 1935-1961 (Box 31, Folder 333)
    This organization provided aid for Jews overseas. Nelson A. Rockefeller headed its 1946 drive, and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $100,000 that year. In 1947, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $25,000. All later appeals were declined. Nelson A. Rockefeller gave annual gifts.
    50.32
  - Jewish Organizations - United Jewish Appeal of Greater New York, 1935-1961 (Box 31, Folder 0333A)
  - Jewish Organizations - United Jewish Appeal of Greater New York - Contributions, 1946-1955 (Box 31, Folder 334)
    Contributions were made by Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, and the Rockefeller Brothers Fund.
  - Jewish Organizations - Union of American Hebrew Congregations, 1951-1954 (Box 31, Folder 335)
    Contributions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel.
    50.33
  - Jewish Organizations - American Joint Distribution Committee, 1926-1952 (Box 31, Folder 336)
    Committee did Jewish relief work. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $100,000 in 1926 but later appeals were declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    50.4
  - Jewish Organizations - American Jewish Committee, 1940-1961 (Box 31, Folder 337)
    David Rockefeller made a contribution in 1955 but other appeals were declined. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
    50.5
  - Jewish Organizations - American Jewish Committee, 1955-1961 (Box 31, Folder 0337A)
  - Jewish Organizations - American Jewish Congress, 1936-1959 (Box 31, Folder 338)
    All invitations and appeals were declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
    50.6
  - Jewish Organizations - Palestine Agencies, 1947-1959 (Box 31, Folder 339)
    All invitations to dinners supporting Israel were declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    50.9
  - Jewish Organizations - Palestine Agencies - American League for a Free Palestine, 1944-1948 (Box 31, Folder 340)
  - Jewish Organizations - Palestine Agencies - American Palestine Committee, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 341)
    All appeals were ignored.
  - Jewish Organizations - Palestine Agencies - American Christian Palestine Committee, 1945-1958 (Box 32, Folder 342)
  - Jewish Organizations - Displaced Persons of All Nationalities, 1933-1960 (Box 32, Folder 343)
    Here are memos regarding various groups seeking to get displaced persons into the United States, and clippings regarding immigration laws. John D. Rockefeller 3rd gave an anonymous contribution to the New England Resettlement Committee. There are also individual appeals. Correspondents include Rodman C. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Freeman, Dana S. Creel.
    50.10
  - Jewish Organizations - Displaced Persons of All Nationalities, 1949-1959 (Box 32, Folder 0343A)
  - Jewish Organizations - Citizens Committee on Displaced Persons, 1947-1950 (Box 32, Folder 344)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and sons gave nominal gifts toward aid for European displaced persons. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, David Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller.
    50.101
  - Jewish Organizations - Citizens Committee on Displaced Persons, 1947-1950 (Box 32, Folder 0344A)
- Negro Organizations
  - Negro Organizations - National League on Urban Conditions Among Negroes, 1911-1918 (Box 32, Folder 345)
    The activities of the league are discussed. Contributions made from 1912-1918. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Willard S. Richardson, Starr J. Murphy.
    111
  - Negro Organizations - Commission on Inter-Racial Cooperation, 1922-1944 (Box 32, Folder 346)
    The Commission sought to improve race relations by gradually increasing contact between whites and Negroes. Contributions were made by the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial Fund and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. from 1922-1923 but later appeals were declined. Activities included anti-lynching movements. There is printed material here. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson.
  - Negro Organizations - Miscellaneous Work among Negroes
    Most special appeals were declined but some small gifts were given. There are reports on various campaigns for improving Negro education and civil rights. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    111.1
    - Negro Organizations - Miscellaneous Work among Negroes, 1930-1945 (Box 32, Folder 347)
    - Negro Organizations - Miscellaneous Work among Negroes, 1946-1950 (Box 32, Folder 348)
    - Negro Organizations - Miscellaneous Work among Negroes, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 0348A)
    - Negro Organizations - Miscellaneous Work among Negroes, 1951-1956 (Box 32, Folder 349)
    - Negro Organizations - Miscellaneous Work among Negroes, 1955-1956 (Box 32, Folder 0349A)
    - Negro Organizations - Miscellaneous Work among Negroes, 1942-1961 (Box 32, Folder 350)
      See also Box 56, Folder 635.
    - Negro Organizations - Miscellaneous Work among Negroes, 1960-1961 (Box 32, Folder 0350A)